Shubham Khirwadkar

khirwadkarshubham09@gmail.com | +1-(972) 799-5914 | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A product-driven Software Engineer with extensive experience in designing backend applications, intuitive UI/UX, automation testing, and DevOps. A proven problem-solver, I excel at optimizing applications and ensuring high code quality through rigorous code reviews and collaborative teamwork. I am passionate about cybersecurity and delivering well-engineered solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Benefit Harbor, LP | Plano, TX

July 2023 - Present

- Designed and implemented a comprehensive insurance portal, building the front end with JavaScript and developing the backend REST APIs with Spring Boot and Hibernate to ensure seamless communication in a microservices environment.
- Developed a comprehensive and automated reporting system for internal use and for external clients, including payroll, invoices, and employee insurance details, which increased operational efficiency for employers and carriers by 50%.
- Optimized SQL queries and database indexing, reducing latency and improving application performance by 60%.
- Supported and maintained a large-scale, monolithic insurance application, working with legacy technologies including JSP, Servlets, JPA, and jQuery to handle new feature requests and bug fixes.

Software Development Engineer | Coreview Systems Pvt Ltd | Pune, MH

Nov 2019 - July 2021

- Helped architect and implement a custom framework from scratch using Python and Django, which was used to design and deliver reliable RESTful APIs for a web application while enforcing coding best practices and ensuring high code quality.
- Architected a robust ETL solution using Apache Airflow and successfully demonstrated its effectiveness in a Proof of Concept (PoC), resolving data issues to achieve a 67% increase in efficiency and 100% data consistency.
- Engineered and automated CI/CD pipelines using Git, Docker, and Jenkins for seamless application deployment on AWS, achieving a 100% deployment success rate.
- Collaborated effectively within a cross-functional Agile team, participating in daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and thorough code reviews to maintain high code quality and ensure successful sprint delivery.

Programmer Analyst | Cognizant Technology Solutions | Pune, MH

July 2018 - Oct 2019

- Engineered a comprehensive test strategy for API testing, defining high-level and low-level test cases that optimized the manual process and enhanced overall test coverage.
- Developed and executed API automation test scripts using Java and Selenium, integrating them into a regression suite to increase test coverage to 87%.

SKILLS

Languages & Web Technologies: Python, Java, JavaScript, SQL, Bash, HTML, CSS, Django, Flask, Spring Boot, React, JavaEE, REST APIs, JSON, Servlets, JSP, jQuery

Cloud & DevOps: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Git, GitHub, JIRA, Apache Airflow

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB

Testing & Tools: Selenium, Appium, TestNg, PyTest, Maven, Swagger

Security: Wireshark, Splunk, Risk Assessment and Management, Vulnerability and Threat Assessment

Methodologies & Concepts: Microservices, Object-Oriented Design (OOD), Agile Development, Distributed Systems

Certifications: Google Cybersecurity, Microsoft Technology Associate Security Fundamentals

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Arlington(GPA: 3.67/4)

Arlington, TX

Master's (MS) in Computer Science

May 2023

Relevant Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Design Patterns, Databases, Cloud Computing, Computer Networks

Vishwakarma Institute of Technology

Pune, MH

Bachelor's (BTech) in Computer Science

May 2018